A Guide to the Rockefeller University records, Laboratory Animal Research Center (LARC), Correspondence FA966
Rockefeller Archive Center
Rockefeller University records, Laboratory Animal Research Center (LARC), Correspondence
1976-1987
Rockefeller Archive Center
Rockefeller University
FA966
3.6 Cubic Feet 3 boxes.
3 boxes.
File Plan note
Former Classification: I 422-2
Arrangement
Arranged in chronological order (in parts) with the rest of the material arranged as received.
Other Finding Aids
FA967 Rockefeller University records, Laboratory Animal Research Center (LARC), Subject Files
Biographical / Historical
Dennis Stark became the director of the new Laboratory Animal Research Center in 1976. In addition to creating an environment conducive to the proper care and housing of animals used for research, Stark launched several research programs. These include a diagnostic laboratory, the Laboratory for In Vitro Toxicological Assay Development, and a program initially funded by Revlon, Inc. to find a non-animal substitute for the Draize ocular irritancy test.
Scope and Contents
Includes primarily correspondence; also includes budget materials, lab notebooks, and a LARC Handbook.
Subjects include Revlon, Inc., the In Vitro Toxicology Lab, and a manual on diagnostic services.
Related Materials
See also: Rockefeller University records, Rockefeller University Press, Publications, Research Profiles.
Conditions Governing Access note
This collection is open for research. Brittle or damaged items are available at the discretion of RAC.
Diseases; Medical technology; Medical research; Pathology; Plant diseases; Biochemistry; Life sciences; Medicine, Preventive; Animals -- Diseases; Medical education; Cell and biomolecular sciences; Technology; Medical sciences; Biology -- Research
- Revlon, Inc., 1983 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Revlon, Inc., 1983-1986 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Revlon, Inc., 1980-1985 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Revlon, Inc., 1980-1982 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Revlon, Inc., 1982-1983 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Revlon, Inc., 1985-1987 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Revlon, Inc., 1986-1987 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Revlon, Inc., 1986-1987 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Revlon, Inc., 1983-1985 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Revlon, Inc., 1984-1985 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Miscellaneous Junk File-Ideas, 1985-1986 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Budgets, 1979-1982 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Budgets, 1978-1979 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Browning/Rockefeller Hybridoma Package, undated (Box 1, Folder 14)
- General Correspondence, 1976-1977 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- General Correspondence, 1977-1978 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- General Correspondence, 1978-1979 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- General Correspondence, 1979-1980 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- General Correspondence, 1980-1981 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- General Correspondence, 1981-1982 (Box 2, Folder 6)
- General Correspondence, 1982-1983 (Box 2, Folder 7)
- General Correspondence, 1983-1984 (Box 2, Folder 8)
- General Correspondence, 1984-1985 (Box 3, Folder 1)
- General Correspondence, 1985-1986 (Box 3, Folder 2)
- General Correspondence, 1985-1986 (Box 3, Folder 3)
- Simpson Trust-In Vitro Toxicology Evaluation Laboratory, 1982 (Box 3, Folder 4)
- Simpson Trust-In Vitro Toxicology Evaluation Laboratory, 1981-1985 (Box 3, Folder 5)
- Microphage Migration Data, 1984 (Box 3, Folder 6)
- Chemotaxis Research, undated (Box 3, Folder 7)
- Diagnostic Services Procedures, I, undated (Box 3, Folder 8)
- Diagnostic Services Procedures, II, undated (Box 3, Folder 9)
- Diagnostic Services Procedures, III, undated (Box 3, Folder 10)
- LARC Handbook, 1985 (Box 3, Folder 11)
- 2 Laboratory Notebooks-Stark, undated (Box 3)